Pravin Bendre

Software Developer

Address 347/183 City Road, Southbank, VIC, 3004

Phone +61 470 630 241

E-mail pravinbendre772@gmail.com

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/pravin772/

GitHub https://github.com/pravin772/

Website https://pravin772.github.io/pravindev/

Multitalented software developer with experience in web, backend, cloud and mobile applications software and services. Demonstrated excellent skills in JavaScript, Java, Golang and Python. True team player with strengths in adaptability and accuracy.

Experience

2020-10 - Present

Application Developer

Milestone IT (Client Austin Health), Melbourne, VIC, AU

- Design, develop and implement functionalities and test
- Evaluate user feedback, fixing bugs, and implementing new features
- Utilising development and deployment tools such as Jira, BitBucket, Azure Cloud and Microsoft services like MSAL, AD authentication
- Creating CI/CD, monitoring builds and deployments
- Contributing to stand-up meetings, sprint review and planning, and brainstorm sessions

2020-06 - 2020-09

Software Development Engineer (Remote)

GeeseTech, Pune, Maharashtra, IND

- Gathering requirements from Store owners, modelling specifications
- Implementing backend services for Retail Store applications
- API calls caching and orchestration, utilising Node.js, Go languages
- Deploying to AWS and integrating AWS services like S3 buckets for storage

2020-03 - 2020-06

Software Development Engineer Intern

Readyteacher, Melbourne, VIC, AU

- Participated in entire software development cycle from start-up specifications to rollout of final product and built AWS infrastructure
- Optimized systems response time by modifying existing Node.js, React code
- Developed various software projects using Node.js and API integrations

2017-05 - 2017-11 Associate .Net Developer

Webtech developers Pvt Ltd, Pune, Maharashtra, IND

- Ported WinForms applications to UWP (Universal Windows Platform)
- Developed team communications and information for stand-up meetings
- Implemented functionalities using C# and XAML for UI forms

Education

2018-07 - 2020-07

Master of Information and Technology: Mobile and Cloud Computing

Swinburne University of Technology - Hawthorn

- Graduated with 3.08 GPA, member of IEEE club
- Specialisation in Mobile and Cloud Computing

2015-07 - 2017-05

Bachelor of Computer Science and Engineering: Computer Science

Shivaji University - Kolhapur

- Graduated in Top 1% of Class
- Graduated with Distinction 76%

Technical Skills

JavaScript, Swift, Golang, Python, Java, C, CPP, HTML, CSS SQL, MySQL, Postgres, NoSQL, MongoDB, Redis, Apache Cassandra, RDS

Flask, Django, Node.js, Express.js, ReactJS, Spark, Vapor, Kitura, JSF

AWS, Azure, MSAL auth, Databricks, Cloud Services, API Development, Web Services, Backend Web Development, GraphQL, Microservices, OpenCV, RabbitMQ, Kafka, Shell, AWS Lambda, Dynamic365, PowerApps

Other Skills

- SDLC, Scrum Agile, SumoLogic, Leadership, Problem Solving
- Slack, Jira, Trello, GitHub, Gitlab, BitBucket CI/CD pipelines. Teams

Projects [GitHub]

Open-source contributions <u>GITHUB</u>, <u>medium.com</u> URL Shortener App [http://weelink.space]

- Frontend ReactJS, Backend APIs Node.js, Postgres DB, Redis cache
- Highly scalable, deployed on cloud, Caching for 20% faster response

Praki, iOS app

- Melbourne CBD public parking slots on map, shows all details on mobile
- Communicates with Apple Map and shows optimized routes

Share List APIs [Click here]

- Server-side Swift, Vapor web framework
- Postgres DB, deployed on cloud, highly scalable

Autonomous Drone to measure Wi-Fi strength and map surroundings

- MongoDB to store Wi-Fi strength and LiDAR sensor data, with Raspberry Pi
- Node.js and Express.js for server, CPP REST client and ROS programming

Certifications

2020-06	Node.js Microservices	2019-12	React.js Essential Training
2020-06	Serverless and Microservices for AWS	2020-06	Go Essential Training

References

Available upon request